我是坐到什么东东啊
What am I sitting on?
"世界之顶"  "河堤码头"
Top of the world? Dock of the bay?
想不出来了
I'm out.
喔  内裤
Oh, ew, undies! Oh.
老实说  谁的
All right, whose are they?
谁的
Whose are they?
不是我的
Not mine.
是乔伊的   一定是他的
Joey's. Got to be Joey's.
的确是我的
They're mine.
看吧  就是乔伊的  乔...伊的
See, Joey's. They're Joe-Joe-Joey's.
怎么会在这里
Why are they here?
我不知道...
I don't know, uh...
因为我是乔伊
I'm Joey.
我生性龌龊  随便在别人家脱内裤
I'm disgusting.I take my underwear off in other people's homes.
快拿走  你有病啊
Get them out of here. What's wrong with you?
对啊  好恶心
Yeah. Yeah.
拿去啊  好...
Take them! I got them.
乔伊  你干嘛不敢碰  这是你自己的内裤
Joey, You can touch them. They're your underwear.
钱德  借步说话  好
Chandler? A word? Yeah.
我受够了  不想再帮你们说谎了
That's it! I'm tired of covering for you two. .
这种鸟事不能再发生了
This has got to stop. Aah
而且还是白色紧身三角裤
Ahh! And tighty-whiteys!
你8岁吗
What are you, 8?
谢谢你  乔伊  感激不尽
Thank you, Joey, so much.
我一点都不情愿
You're not welcome, okay?
我讨厌这样
Look, I hate this.
你们总是害我出丑
You guys keep embarrassing me.
昨天瑞秋在这的浴室  看到你的剃毛刀
Yesterday, Rachel found your razor in our bathroom.
我不知道怎么回答
and I didn't know what to say,
只好说是我的
so I said it was mine
还说我要在话剧里演女人
and-and that I was playing a woman in a play.
结果还得一不做二不休
Then one thing led to another and...
哇  连脚踝周围都剃光了  那里很不好刮啊
And around the ankles, that is a tough spot.
没错  告诉你们  我不能...
Yeah, It was. All right, listen...
要说谎我们也不好受
All this lying has been hard on us too.
是啊  不过至少你们有上床
Yeah, I bet all the sex makes it easier.
那倒是
Yeah, actually.
我们下次一定会更小心
We'll be more careful.
因为我们实在太顺利了  所以还不想让别人知道
we don't want everyone to know because this is going really well
搞不好就是保密才能这么顺利
and maybe the reason it's going really well is because it's a secret..
我知道你觉得很怪  但我们都不太会处理感情问题
I know it sounds really weird, but we're so bad at relationships.
没错  帮帮忙  拜托
We are. Help us. Help.
好吧  不过...
All right. But,
你要跟我上一次床
you do it with me once.
乔伊  就知道你不肯
Joey! Didn't think so.
老友记  第五季  第09集  罗斯的三明治
Friends  S05E09 The One With Ross's Sandwich
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
嗨  菲比
Hey, Phoebe.
Hey, Pheebs.
你在看什么
What are you reading?
"呼啸山庄"
Um, Wuthering Heights.
我在纽恩大学上文学课  明天之前必须看完第一章
I'm taking a literature class at the New School and I have to finish it for the first session tomorrow.
我不知道你在上课  真酷
I didn't know you were taking a class. That is so cool.
上次上拉梅兹的课很好玩
I really liked that Lamaze class I took.
所以我决定换堂课来上上   换个比较要用脑袋的
Y'know and this time I thought I'd go for something, y'know a little more intellectual,
期末考又不用那么痛苦的
...with a less painful final exam.
听起来很有意思
Honey that sounds like fun.
对  你也可以一起来
Yeah! Oh, you should come with me!
就有人可以跟我一起坐了
Oh yeah, Then I'll have someone to sit with.
好啊
Okay.
不过你有时间看书吗
Yeah! Okay―ooh, but are you going to have time to read it?
我高中就读过了
Oh, I read that in high school.
一定很好玩
This is going to be so much fun! .
嘘  先让我看完
Okay-shhh, I have to finish
嗨
Hi.
嗨  你怎么啦
What's wrong, buddy?
有同事偷吃我的三明治
Someone at work ate my sandwich.
条子怎么说
What did the police say?
那是感恩节剩下的三明治
My Thanksgiving leftover sandwich.
竟然给人偷吃掉
I can't believe someone ate it.
罗斯  不过是个三明治嘛
Ross, It's just a sandwich.
不过是个三明治
Just a sandwich?
我今年30岁  已经离婚两次  还没地方可住
Look, I am 30 years old, okay? I'm about to be divorced twice and I just got evicted!
那个三明治是我人生中  唯一美好的事物
That sandwich was the only good thing going on in my life!
我唯一美好的事物  竟然给人偷吃掉
Someone ate the only good thing going on in my life!
我还有材料可以再做一个
I have enough stuff for one more sandwich,
我本来自己要吃...
I was going to eat it myself, but...
太好了  真是谢谢你
Mon, that would be incredible. Thank you so much.
我到现在还不相信有人偷吃了
I still can't believe someone ate it!
我还留了一张纸条在上面
Look, I left a note and everything.
喂  谁啊
"Knock-knock." "Who's there?"
罗斯盖勒的午餐
"Ross Geller's lunch."
哪个罗斯盖勒的午餐
"Ross Geller's lunch, who?"
这是罗斯盖勒的午餐  请勿偷走我  好吗"
"Ross Geller's lunch. Please don't take me. Okay?"
你没被扁  就该偷笑了
I'm surprised you didn't go home wearing your lunch.
不想让别人偷吃你的东西
Okay, look you wanna hold onto your food?
那就得吓吓他们  这是我在街头流浪学到的
You gotta scare people off. I learned that living on the street.
真的  你会怎么说  菲比
Really? So what would you say Pheebs?
比如 "脏手少碰我的馊水"
Stuff like, uh, "Keep your mitts off my grub."
罗斯  你以为菲比当年是在演《安妮》吗
Say Ross, when you picture Phoebe living on the street, is she surrounded by the entire cast of Annie?
贴上这张纸条就没人敢偷吃了
Okay, This'll keep them away from your stuff.
哇...
Whoa! Ohh!!
菲比  你真狠
Phoebe, you are a badass!
下次再告诉你们  我拿刀捅条子的事
Someday I'll, tell you about the time I stabbed the cop.
菲比  是他先捅我的
Phoebe. He stabbed me first!
布朗蒂姊妹是当代的杰出女性
The Bronte sisters were remarkable women for their time.
当时是父系社会
They lived in a patriarchal society.
抱歉迟到了  因为我出门太晚了
Sorry I'm late, but I left late.
好吧
Ahem. Okay.
菲比  这本书说什么
So Pheebs, what is the book about?
你说你高中念过
Didn't you read it in high school?
对  后来我想起我开始看时  正好碰上要为球队打气
Well yeah, but then I remembered I started it and there was this pep rally and I was,
我又是啦啦队的队长
I was on top of the pyramid .
就是这样啦  到底在说什么
but anyway.umm, what is this book about?
这是凯西跟希克里夫的悲惨爱情故事
Okay, umm, It's a tragic love story between Cathy and Heathcliff.
故事发生在英国一座恐怖的山庄
and umm, It takes place on these creepy moors in England.
场景就代表  男主角性格中狂野的一面
Which I think represent the wildness of Heathcliff's character.
我对象征主义很有一套
I totally get symbolism.
这本书的主题是什么
How would you characterize the theme of this book?
看看找谁  瑞秋葛林
Uh, let's see... Rachel Green?
这是个爱情悲剧
Umm, well I would have to say that it's a tragic love story.
非常明显  不过你说得也没错
That's sort of a given...but, yes.
还有谁有意见
Anyone else?
还有象征性的意义
Oh, oh, oh. Symbolism!
狂野的场景...
And uh, the-the uh, wildness of the mores...
我觉得反映出  男主角性格中桀骜的一面
which I think is mirrored in the wildness of  Heathcliff's character.
非常好
Excellent!
瑞秋读得相当透彻
What Rachel has shrewdly observed here...
你根本就是照我说的回答
You completely stole my answer!
亲爱的  随便看看就知道了
Honey, that was pretty obvious.
你哪晓得  你根本没看过
Well how would you know? You didn't read it!
你有意见
What do you think?
穿蓝衬衫这位同学
Uh, you in the blue shirt?
我认为这个问题  有很多可能的答案
I think that, um, yours is a question with many possible answers.
那就麻烦你举出一个
Would you care to venture one?
你愿意说一个吗
你是重复我的话吗
Are you just repeating what I'm saying?
好吧  我们继续
All right. Let's move on.
好
Okay, then.
你为什么不直接说你没看过
Why didn't you say you hadn't read the book?
我不希望他认为我很蠢
because I didn't want him to think I was stupid.
你看看你多蠢啊
That was really embarrassing, what happened to you.
菲比  什么
Phoebe! Phoebe! Yeah?
你那张纸条  真是了不起
Your note? Amazing!
不但没人敢碰我的三明治
Not only did no one touch my sandwich...
而且还开始对我敬畏三分
...but people at work are actually afraid of me.
还有人叫我 "疯子"  "疯子盖勒"
A guy called me "Mental.""Mental Geller."
我一直梦想有这种超酷的外号
I've always wanted a cool nickname like that.
以前你最酷的外号  就是 "尿裤子盖勒"
The best you got in high school was, uh, "Wet Pants Geller."
那是饮水机喷到的
That was the water fountain, okay?
现在有人愿意帮我写报告
Anyway...people are writing reports for me...
我爱什么时候交就什么时候交
...uh, pushing back deadlines to fit my schedule.
原来对人耍狠  就可以呼风唤雨
I tell you, you get tough with people and you can get anything you want.
崔比亚尼  咖啡拿来
Hey, Tribbiani! Give me that coffee! Now!
今天真有意思
This was really fun.
我本来还怀疑你会不会约我
I've been wondering if you'd ask me out.
你还在怀疑吗
So you, uh, still wondering?
不  我们刚刚才约过会啊
No. We just went out.
你真聪明  我喜欢
You're smart.I like that.
还有蜡烛啊
Oh, candles!
这是什么  毯子  摄影机  我的天啊
What is that, a blanket?A video camera? Oh, my God!
不是这样...等等啊
No, no, no. Wait.
不敢相信你竟然在第一次约会  就想拍下我们上床过程
I can't believe you thought you'd video tape us having sex on the first date!
你好
Hi.
乔伊  她刚说的...
Joey, is what she just said, um...
天啊  你还真打算...
Oh, my God!You're actually gonna
这是怎么回事
What is going on here?
而且钱德还在家  你是...你变态吗
And with Chandler in the next room. What are you, what are you sick?
我是乔伊啊
I'm Joey.
我本来就很恶心
I mean, I'm disgusting.
还拍低成本的色情片
I make low-budget adult films.
你们答应我  要更小心的
You guys promised to be more careful!
乔伊的好名声都给你们毁了
I mean, come on! The good Joey name is being dragged through the mud here!
对不起  抱歉
We're so sorry.
我要把你们的事情说出去
Well, I'm telling everyone about you!
否则内裤跟摄影机的事  只会让人觉得  我是变态猪啰
That's the only way to explain the underwear and the video camera that doesn't make me look like a pig!
不-不  等一下  一定有其他方法
No-no, wait! There's got to be a better explanation.
你可以说你在拍色情片  因为你在...上色情片的课
You can tell them you had to make an adult film for your...adult film class.
这理由还不错  不行
Yeah, I like that. But no-no,
瑞秋在你家  发现我内裤的事又怎么说
how does that explain why Rachel found my underwear at your place?
不知道
I don't know.
看来你们得出柜承认了
Well, get ready to come out of the non-gay closet!
拜托你等等  我保证一定会想出理由
Okay, just wait, please.I promise to come up with something.
再让我们多缓几天
Just give us a little more time.
好吧  最好让我能保住面子
All right Hey, but it better make me look really, really good.
还有...摄影机
Oh, and another thing, the video camera?
了不起
Nice!
（史前历史博物馆）
罗斯  可以跟你谈谈吗
Umm, Ross. May I have a word with you?
当然  唐诺
Of course, Donald.
有同事抱怨你最近脾气火爆
We've been getting reports of some very angry behavior on your part.
什么
What? .
写信威胁大家  拒绝按时交报告
Threatening letters..refusal to meet deadlines.
还有人叫你是 "疯子"
Apparently people now call you Mental.
是啊
Yeah.
我们希望你找精神科医生谈谈
We want you to speak to a psychiatrist.
不  你不懂  其实是误会
Oh, no. Uh, you...You don't understand. This is so silly.
一切要从我的三明治说起
Um, this is all just because of a sandwich.
三明治
A sandwich?
我妹妹非常会做火鸡三明治
You see, my sister makes these amazing turkey sandwiches.
她的秘诀就是  多夹一片浸过肉汁的面包在中间
Her secret is, she puts an extra slice of gravy-soaked bread in the middle.
我称那片为 "多汁秘方"
I call it "The Moistmaker."
有一次我把三明治放在冰箱
Anyway, I put my sandwich in the fridge...
你知道吗  什么
Ha-ha-ha. Oh, you know what?
对不起  应该是我吃掉了
I'm sorry.I believe I ate that.
你吃了我的三明治
You ate my sandwich?
我一时看错  谁都可能拿错
A simple mistake. It can happen to anyone.
是吗
Oh, really?
难道你的三明治  也有"多汁秘方"
Did you confuse it with your own turkey sandwich with a Moistmaker?
没有  难道你没看到上面的纸条
No, I...Do you, perhaps, remember...seeing a note on top of it?
我以为那是有人开玩笑  或是随手写的打油诗
There may have been a joke or limerick of some kind.
上面清楚写着那是我的三明治
That said it was...my sandwich!
你别激动
Now calm down.
可以到我办公室找找  可能垃圾筒里还有剩
Come look in my office, some of it my still be in the trash.
什么
What?
那个三明治很大
Well, it was quite large.
我必须丢掉一大半
I-I-I-I-I had to throw most of it away.
你...丢掉我的三明治
You-you-you-you threw my sandwich away?
我的三明治
My sandwich?
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi.
这本书在讲什么
So umm, What's this book about?
这本你也没看
You didn't read it, either?
我本来是要看  结果却看了其它的书
Well, I was going to, but I, uh, accidentally read something else.
什么
What?
时尚杂志
Vogue.
跟我说这本《简爱》是在说什么
Hey, So tell me about Jane Eyre.
不行  你应该自己看
No, You should've read it yourself!
菲比  别这么假正经嘛
Come on Phoebe! don't be such a goody-goody.
好吧
Fine.
简爱呢  你会以为她是女人  其实不然
Okay, all right. So Jane Eyre? First you'd think she's a woman, but she's not.
她是生化人
She's a cyborg.
生化人  就是机器人
A cyborg? Isn't that like a robot?
这本书在当时超级先进
Yeah, This book was light years ahead of its time.
抱歉迟到  开始上课吧
Sorry I'm late. Let's get started.
大家对《简爱》有何感想
So, What did you think of Jane Eyre?
瑞秋刚跟我讨论过  她有些看法非常有趣
Um, Rachel and I were discussing it, and she actually had very interesting insights.
请说  瑞秋
Go ahead, Rachel.
谢谢你  菲比
Um, thank you, Phoebe.
《简爱》最让我震惊的就是
Umm, well, What struck me most when reading Jane Eyre...
这本书非常惊世骇俗
...was, uh, how the book was so ahead of its time.
如果你指的是女性主义  这么说也成
If you're talking about feminism, I think you're right.
当然有写到女性主义  不过还有机器人
Well, feminism, yes. But also the robots.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
既然上次拍摄不成功
Since that video camera thing didn't work out...
我先给你一点预告片段
...I thought that I would give you just a little preview.
你在照片中没穿衣服
You're naked in this picture!
我知道
I know!
罗斯
Ross?
钱德
Hey, Chandler.
摩妮卡
Monica!
罗斯  你没事吧
Ross, Are you okay?
我很好
I'm fine.
我今天上班去看过精神医生
I saw a psychiatrist at work today.
为什么
Why?
因为我脾气太暴躁
On account of my rage.
而且最近越来越严重
Which, if I may say, right now is out of control.
所以他开药丸给我
He gave me a pill for it.
药丸
A pill?
医生说我对上司大吼大叫
Uh-huh. When the psychiatrist told me to take a leave of absence...
所以应该请假
...because I yelled at my boss,
我又开始暴跳如雷
I started to get worked up again.
所以他要我吃颗镇定剂
So he offered me a tranquilizer.
我觉得这主意不错
And I thought it was a good idea.
所以就吃了
So I took it.
等等  他们逼你请假
Wait a minute, They're making you take time off work?
而且你也同意
And you're okay with that?
我不知道
I don't know.
刚开始不工作可能不习惯
It's going to be weird not having a job for a while.
不过我已经不在乎三明治了
But I definitely don't care about my sandwich.
我丢脸丢大了  你竟然还让我一直说下去
That's so embarrassing! I can't believe you let me go on like that!
对不起
I'm sorry.
你把简爱比成机器战警  实在太爆笑了
It was just so funny when you started comparing Jane Eyre to Robocop.
一点也不好笑
That was not funny!
我太气了
I snapped, okay?
你根本不想好好上课
You weren't taking the class seriously.
菲比  这有什么了不起
Phoebe, Come on! What is the big deal?
我以为我们就是一起出去
I thought it'd be something we could do together.
上课打发时间闹着玩
Y'know, I thought it would be fun.
好玩很重要
Well, yeah! Fun is good.
但是我也想学点东西
but y'know I also wanted to learn.
大家老说在高中学东学西  我却没上过高中
People talk about what they learned in high school. I never went to high school.
所以你真的想学东西
Ohh. Oh, So you really wanted to learn.
但是  菲比  我只想找点乐子
Yeah, y'know, Pheebs, I just wanted to have fun.
你知道你该拉谁去吗
Ohh, you know who you should go with?
我知道...
I know! I know! I know!
摩妮卡  问题是你提的
Monica, you asked the question.
天啊  是摩妮卡
Oh, my God, that's Monica!
不是这样...你别误会
Oh, no, no, no!
离我远点  你这个大变态
You get away from me, You sick, sick, sick, sick-o!!
怎么啦
What's going on?
乔伊有偷窥癖
Joey has got a secret peephole!
天啊...
Oh, no, no, no, no!
对  他有摩妮卡的裸体照片
Yes! He has a naked picture of Monica!
他拍下我们裸体的样子
He takes naked pictures of us,
还一边吃鸡块一边看
then he eats chicken and looks at them!
你们看  那是我老妹啊
Look. Oh! Dude, that's my sister!
给我  等下  大家先别激动
Give me that! All right, Wait! Everybody just calm down. Okay?
要给我们的老友乔伊  有机会解释他为何如此变态
Let's give our friend Joey a chance to explain why he's such a big pervert!
我不是变态好吗
No! I am not a pervert! Okay?
只是...我...其实...
It's just...I just kind of...
大家听我说  我可以帮他解释
All right, look! Look. I think I can explain this.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔伊是性爱狂
Joey's a sex addict.
什么  才怪
What? No, I'm not!
没关系  不怪你
It's okay! It's good! It's good.
这只是一种病
It's a disease.
胡说  我才不是性爱狂
No! No! I am not a sex addict!
你明明就是
Yes, you are!
这才能解释最近这一连串的事
That's the only way to explain all this stuff!
事实不是这样
No, it isn't. No, it's not.
你也可以说出真相
Because you could also explain it with the truth!
什么真相
What is the truth?
怎么回事  你在说什么
What's up? What's going on?
我跟摩妮卡上床了
I slept with Monica.
听听大家怎么说
Well, let's see what everybody thinks of that.
天啊
Oh, no.
你跟我老妹上床
You slept with my sister?
对  只在伦敦发生过一次
Uh, yes, but it was...We just did it once, uh, in London.
这会让我开始抓狂
This is not good for my rage.
摩妮卡  是真的吗
Monica.Is this true?
当然是真的
Of course, it's true.
否则怎么解释这些怪事
How else would you explain all the weird stuff that's been going on?
是真的
Yes, it's true.
如果只发生过一次
Okay, but if it only happened that one time,
你的内裤  怎么会出现在我们家
how come we found your underwear in our apartment the other day?
那件内裤是我当天在伦敦穿的  对不对  摩妮卡
That was the underwear I was wearing that night in London. Right Monica?
我想留下来...当纪念品
I guess I wanted to keep it...as a souvenir.
天啊  摩妮卡
My God, Monica!
你确定  乔伊  你确定你不是性爱狂
Are you sure Joe? Are you sure you're not just a sex addict?
不  要是有人是性爱狂  那也是摩妮卡
No! If anyone's a sex addict here, it's Monica!
没错  打我们从伦敦回来  她就想再勾引我上床
Yeah. She has been trying to get me back in the sack ever since London!
所以她才拍裸照给你
That's why she gave you a naked picture of herself.
这样说得通
That makes sense.
录影机呢
And the video camera?
摩妮卡
Uh, Monica?
我架好录影机是为了引诱乔伊上钩
I guess I set up the video camera to try and entice Joey.
可惜我不吃这套
But, sadly, I could not be enticed.
不可思议  你还留下乔伊的内裤
Unbelievable! You really kept Joey's underwear?
为什么  你为什么这么做
Why? Why would you do that?
因为我是摩妮卡
I'm Monica.
生性下流
I'm disgusting.
我会跟踪男人  留下他们的内裤
I stalk guys and keep their underpants.
现在终于知道谁是恶心鬼了
Well, I think we've all learned something about who's disgusting and who's not. Eh?
好了  我要开始吃炸鸡了
All right. Now, I'm going to get back to my bucket.
我只吃鸡皮  你们可以吃鸡肉
I'm only eating the skin, so the chicken's up for grabs.
你说得很有道理
I really thought you making a good point.
可惜后来被打断
I mean y'know, until you got cut off.
我知道  那个摩妮卡哪里有病啊
What's up with that girl Monica?
谁晓得  她不是我朋友
I don't know. I didn't come with her.
好消息  各位  你们猜怎么了
Hey, everybody! Everybody, guess what!
我说服卡尔下周考试
I just convinced Carl to give us a test next week!.
考试
Test?
开心点  有考试才有进步
Come on! Tests make us all better learners!
对了  应该考申论题
Oh, yeah! We should have essay questions!